Detroit Copper Mining Company records, 1882-1919
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Detroit Copper Mining Company records, 1882-1919
AZ 163
Detroit Copper Mining Company
Financial journals, payrolls, time books, and ore and freight records related to mining company operations. Includes financial records of Hotel Morenci (1904-1913) and Frisco Ranch (1909-1913).
6 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Copper mining company operations near Clifton and Morenci, Arizona, started in 1875 by William Church. Phelps Dodge purchased an interest in the company in 1881 and bought Church out in 1897. After a 1917 reorganization, the operation was known as Phelps Dodge Corporation, Morenci Branch.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Financial Records, 1883-1914
Series II: Hotel Morenci Financial and Payroll Records, 1904-1919
Series III: Payroll and Time Books, 1882-1911
Scope and Content Note
Financial journals, payrolls, time books, and ore and freight records related to mining company operations. Includes financial records of Hotel Morenci (1904-1913) and Frisco Ranch (1909-1913).
Access Terms
Detroit Copper Mining Company -- Archives
Hotel Morenci -- Records and correspondence
Frisco Ranch -- Records and correspondence
Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Greenlee County -- History -- Sources
Mineral industries -- Arizona -- Finance -- Sources
Copper miners -- History -- Sources
Hotels -- Arizona -- Morenci -- History -- Sources
Payrolls
Account books
Journals
Related Material
Additional payroll records and time books are on microfilm no. 2957.
Container List
- Series I: Financial Records, 1883-1914
  - Journal. September 1883-August 1885 (Volume 1)
  - Journal. September 1885-December 1892 (Volume 2)
  - Journal. January 1893-December 1898 (Volume 3)
  - Journal. January 1911-March 1913 (Volume 4)
  - Engine Record (West Yankie Concentrator). July 1911-February 1913 (Volume 5)
  - Freight Record. October 1910-September 1914 (Volume 6)
- Series II: Hotel Morenci Payroll and Financial Records, 1904-1919
  - Hotel Morenci Ledger. 1904-1905 (Volume 7)
  - Hotel Morenci Cash Book. January 1908-November 1910 (Volume 8)
  - Hotel Morenci Financial Records (various). 1909-1913 (Volume 9)
  - Miscellaneous Records. 1900-1919 (Box 10)
    Includes:
    Four Morenci Time Books, October 1902-January 1919
    Price Note books, Charge Book, 1914-1915
    Statement of Operations at Reduction Works, 1900
    Stable and Forage Records (time books), 1906-1912
    Draft Register
    Frisco Ranch
- Series III: Series III: Payroll and Time Books, 1882-1911
  - Payroll. 1882-1889 (Box 11)
  - Payroll. 1890-1894 (Box 12)
  - Payroll. 1895-1897 (Box 13)
  - Time Book and Payroll. June 1897-July 1898 (Volume 14)
  - Time Book and Payroll. August 1898-May 1899 (Volume 15)
  - Time Book and Payroll. May-December 1899 (Volume 16)
  - Time Book and Payroll. January-February 1900 (Volume 17)
  - Ore Record. 1904-1911 (Volume 18)